\_\_Resume\_\_\_

# **SAMI BEN DIKOU**



## SENIOR INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY PROFESSIONAL

Over 11 Years of Experience on various Senior Management Positions in Germany & UAE

Abu Dhabi – United Arab Emirates Mobile No: +971 56 895 0742

Email: <a href="mailto:bendikou@hotmail.de">bendikou@hotmail.de</a>

Linked in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sami-ben-dikou-22957b21/

# **SAMI BEN DIKOU**

Abu Dhabi – United Arab Emirates

Mobile No: +971 56 895 0742 | Email: ?@outlook.com

# SENIOR IT PROFESSIONAL – REGIONAL IT MANAGER (UAE)

Creative, innovative and forward-thinking Information Technology Manager who solves complex business and IT challenges with thoughtful, elegant and clearly defined strategies that drive revenue growth; with **11+ years' rich experience in managing and troubleshooting IT issues and driving high-end strategic business models.** A leader who uses "out-of-the-box" approach to problem solving, and consistently drive bottom-line performance, efficiency process and profit improvements.

- ✓ **Business strategist** plan and manage million worth projects aligning business goals with technology solutions to drive process improvements, competitive advantage and bottom-line gains.
- ✓ **Excellent communicator** leverage technical, business and financial acumen to communicate effectively with client executives and their respective teams.

#### ---- Core Competencies ----

#### **IT Management:**

- IT Operations Managemnt
- IT Network Administration
- Systems Engineering
- System Migrations/ Integrations
- Enterprisewide Implementations

#### **IT Project Lifecycle:**

- Requirements Analysis
- ROI Analysis
- Costing & Budgeting
- Project Scheduling
- Testing/QA/Rollout/Support

#### Value-Added Leadership:

- Cross-Functional Supervision
- Team Building & Mentoring
- Client Relations & Presentations
- Business & IT Planning
- Vendor Management

#### **BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Provided leadership and vision for the IT department include strategic planning of information systems.
- Developed strategic direction for the information systems plan including technology deployment plans and departmental budgets.
- Directed all information technology and network system deployment and maintenance including all IT infrastructure, wireless communications, PC systems, local networks and mobile environment.
- Managed IT training for IT staff members and end user training on software and desktop systems.
- Created operational policies, procedures, standards, guidelines and best practices.
- Recruited, hired and trained IT staff, project managers, engineer and network administrators.
- Ensured project completion by coordinating resources and timetables with user departments, IT staff and data center employees.
- Created financial forecasts, outline expenditures and modifed budget when necessary.
- Assessed new innovative technologies, mission critical systems, security, communications and business continuity.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### **REGIONAL IT MANAGER**

#### Xervon Industrial Services LLC, Abu Dhabi UAE

Jan 2016 – Present

- Xervon Industrial Services LLC is an Electrical and Electronic Manufacturing company.
- Lead and manage multiple complex and strategic projects through on-time delivery, often partnering closely with the internal business and IT organization as well as third party vendors.
- Drive the continuous deployment of cutting-edge application features, functionalities and integrations that allow users to deliver to their KPIs more effectively and efficiently.
- Continuously iterate and improve the project delivery lifecycle.
- Designing and planning the IT Infrastructure, and support Operation project with IT based solutions.
- Manage and negotiating agreements with suppliers and providers for MENA region.
- Oversee department meetings with staff leads and managers to ensure continuity of information systems support and goal attainment.
- Successfully deploy Networking & Security: VoIP, WiFi, Firewall, EPS system throughout entire organization in saving over seventy thousand dollars in communication maintenance costs annually.
- Support and manage 2 different domains in GCC provide IT services to all Xervon companies in GCC countries.
- Monitor, measure and communicate project performance against delivery scope, budget, timeline, and stakeholder satisfaction as well as the estimated ROI.
- Effectively prepare and present large-scale projects to the board of directors.

- Create computer security policy and disaster recovery procedures.
- Implement hardware and software upgrades to several mission critical applications.
- Establish change management and help desk solutions and policies.
- Develop strong interpersonal relationships with key stakeholders to drive effective partnerships.

#### **IT TEAM LEAD**

#### Remondis Maintenance & Services GmbH, Germany

Jan 2015 – Dec 2015

- Support team manager and performs management duties.
- Manage inventories and stock, including keeping detailed records of inventory use and sales, and advising management on ordering where necessary.
- Provide encouragement to team members, including communicating team goals and identifying areas for new training or skill checks.
- Assist management with hiring processes and new team member training.
- Answer team member questions, helps with team member problems, and oversees team member work for quality and guideline compliance.
- Communicate deadlines and sales goals to team members.
- Develop strategies to promote team member adherence to company regulations and performance goals.
- Conduct team meetings to update members on best practices and continuing expectations.
- Generate and share comprehensive and detailed reports about team performance, mission-related objectives, and deadlines.
- Ensure company brand materials and physical working spaces meet and exceed company presentation standards.
- Provide quality customer service, including interacting with customers, answering customer enquiries, and effectively handling customer complaints.

#### **IT SUPPORTER**

#### Remondis Maintenance & Services GmbH, Germany

Dec 2006 - Dec 2014

- Working closely with the IT Manager and Director to ensure all targets are met.
- Provide desktop hardware support.
- Helpdesk member Focal contact Person for Buchen Belgium & for Buchen France
- Support in SAP translation from German to French.
- Updating equipment and providing user documentation.
- Providing internal IT support; answering any technical questions and helping staff resolve issues.
- Ensure smooth running of IT systems and that tracking and monitoring of performance is carried out, metrics and reports are analysed.
- Responding/resolving any issues efficiently.
- Keeping up to date with the latest software.
- Responsible for monitoring core network and alerting Infrastructure teams to any incidents.
- Proactively identify reoccurring faults and ensure a full resolution is implemented to prevent further incidents.

#### **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**

Graduation – Physics – University of Manchester, Manchester, England – Sep 1999 – May 2004 Graduation – Physics – University of Manchester, Manchester, England – Sep 1999 – May 2004

### **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION/ MEMBERSHIPS**

ILM Strategy Execution – ShiftIn, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia– Apr 2015NEBOSH Health & Safety at Work – EITC, Al-Khobar, Saudi Arabia– Jan 2012NEBOSH International General Certificate – Petrofac, Sharjah, UAE– Oct 2007

#### **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**

Age: 36 Years | Nationality: German | Languages: English, German, Arabic and French